Guide to the Kathe Burkhart Papers MSS.467
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Artwork, 1965-2017; 11.25 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes, 2 record cartons, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 1 flat-file folder.; 165.5 Gigabytes in 3,814 computer files.; 15 videocassettes (u-matic); 3 audiocassettes; 2 videocassettes (vhs); 1 videocassettes (minidv); 5 film reels
  - Photograph -- Large-scale Image of Woman Playing Cello Overlaid with Graphic Images, undated; cuid36448 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - "Me, Missy", undated; cuid36449 (Box 46, Super 8mm film reel 467.0019)
  - "Feet", undated; cuid36450 (Box 46, Super 8mm film reel 467.0020)
  - "Siamese Feet", undated; cuid36452 (Box 46, Super 8mm film reel 467.0022)
  - "Siamese Feet" Soundtrack, undated; cuid39075 (Box Shared Fales 094, Audiocassette 467.0039)
    Duration: 62 minutes
  - "Sea Shore", undated; cuid36453 (Box 46, Super 8mm film reel 467.0023)
  - Personal Video Essay and Two Family Interviews, undated; cuid36454 (Box 46, Minidv 467.0001)
    Duration: 7 minutes
- Series II. The Liz Taylor Series, 1960-2018; 5.17 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 1 record carton, 1 flat file box, and 2 oversize boxes.; 4 Gigabytes in 882 computer files.; 1 sound cassettes (dat)
  Burkhart's The Liz Taylor Series (1982-ongoing) is a self-portrait project in which the artist uses the image of actress Elizabeth Taylor to explore fantasies and evoke the artists genderqueer identity. Stills of Taylor taken from her films are painted in a cartoonish style with profane text superimposed over the work. This series contains material related to the creation, sale, promotion, and exhibition of these artworks.
  A large collection of source material specifically related to Elizabeth Taylor was accumulated over decades by Burkhart and used as inspiration and background research for her artworks. Source material is in print and electronic form, and includes issues of gossip magazines, commercial publications, special edition publications, fan magazines, press clippings, authorized and unauthorized biographies, and also film stills and promotional images of Taylor alone and with others. Word type treatments used when superimposing words over the artworks are in this series. Files in this series also contain correspondence, sales invoices, consignment agreements, donation forms for fundraisers, exhibition promotional material, and images of artworks and exhibition installations. Additional material related to this painting series can be found throughout the collection.
  - Liz Taylor Source Material -- Fan Magazines, Articles, Clippings, Movie Still Images, 1960-2011 (Box 11, Folder 14-15, Box 12, Folder 1-3, Box 17, Folder 1-9, Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Liz Taylor Source Images, 2011-2014; cuid36219 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_36)
  - Liz Taylor Source Material -- Books, T-shirt, 1962-2011 (Box 13, Box 14, Box 67)
  - Artist Statements and Descriptions, 1985-2012, undated; cuid36220 (Box 12, Folder 4, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_31)
  - Artwork Images, circa 1985-2018; cuid36221 (Box 12, Folder 5, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_32)
  - Word Type Treatments and Graphics for Artworks, circa 1980s-2000s; cuid36222 (Box 12, Folder 6-8, Box 17, Folder 11, Box 28, Folder 6, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_38)
  - Exhibition Promotional Material, Images, and Catalogs, 1982-2016; cuid36223 (Box 15, Folder 1-6, Box 17, Folder 10, Box 28, Folder 7, Box 44, Folder 3, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_34)
  - Artwork Images Used as Illustrations and in Publications, 1987-1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition Opening Reception Guest Book, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Articles and Reviews, 1988-2018 (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - Consignment Agreements and Copyright Form, 1993, 2007, 2016-2017 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Artwork Invoices and Donations, 1993-2017; cuid36224 (Box 16, Folder 6, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_35)
  - Loans, Consignments, Donations -- Forms, 1994-2014; cuid36225 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_37)
  - Artwork Lists, 2007, 2014-2015; cuid36226 (Box 16, Folder 7, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_33)
  - Exhibition Planning Files, 2008-2016 (Box 16, Folder 8-11)
  - The Liz Taylor Series Press Kit, 2016 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Homewrecker -- Artwork Mock-Up, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Burkhart, Taylor Recording, undated (Box 46, Dat 467.0002)
- Series III. Writing, 1983-2014; 7.17 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes, 1 record carton, 1 flat box, and 1 oversize flat box.; 485 Megabytes in 351 computer files.; 4 audiocassettes; 1 videocassettes (vhs)
  This series contains material related to Burhart's poems, haikus, short stories, articles, and novels. Files in this series include short published pieces, work files for novels, and recordings of readings and performances. Drafts, notes, and published versions of poems, haikus, short stories, as well as review articles by Burkhart are also in this series. A significant amount of the paper and electronic files in this series pertain to the creation of various Burkhart books, including From Under the 8-Ball (published in 1985), The Double Standard (published in 2002 and 2005), The Double Standard (published in 2005), and Dudes (published in 2014). These files contain drafts, research, page and cover layouts, and correspondence with publishers, agents, and friends. Burkhart's 2006 novel Between the Lines was inspired by letters sent to her Aunt Grace Knipe from her friend Kate Gibson. Paper and electronic files related to the writing and publishing of this novel include research, drafts, page layouts, and correspondence. The original letters are in Series VII.
  - "Feminism in the Art School?" in the WALT CalArts Publication, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Lace Book Store -- Budget, Supply List, Business Plan, 1983-1986 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Reviews Written by Burkhart, 1984-1986, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Readings and Related Events -- Promotional Material, 1984-1998, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - "I Had a Dream" in Hudson Center Journal, December 1985 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Kathe Burkhart -- "On the Dole", 1985; cuid39234 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0005)
    Duration: 5 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
  - Kathe Burkhart -- "On the Dole", 1985; cuid39235 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0006)
    Duration: 14 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
  - High Performance Magazine -- Writer Guidelines, Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - From Under the 8-Ball (1985) -- Edited Typescripts, Funding, Page Proof Layouts, circa 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1-5)
  - From Under the 8-Ball (1985) -- Excerpt and Cover Layout, 1985-1986 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - From Under the 8-Ball (1985) -- Cover Image, circa 1985; cuid36227 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_46)
  - Correspondence, 1985-2014 (Box 19, Folder 6-9)
  - "Everyman" in New Leaves Review, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Untitled Poem in National Poetry Magazine of the Lower East Side, February 1986 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - "Prescriptive" in New Leaves Review, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - "The Milk Truck" in Farm and Alternator Magazine, 1987-1988 (Box 19, Folder 13, Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Burkhart Books and Readings -- Articles and Reviews, 1988-2006 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Collection of Poems-- Typescripts, circa 1985-1991 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Theatrical Piece -- Jail of Gender -- Program, Script, Promotional Material, Layout, circa 1990s (Box 20, Folder 4, Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "The Broken Record" in Slut Magazine, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Reading at Feature Gallery, 1991; cuid39236 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0007)
    Duration: 26 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
  - Reading / Spoken Word Performance at Feature Gallery, 1992; cuid39237 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0008)
    Duration: 27 minutes; Preservation note: Side 2 is blank
  - Bomb Magazine, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "Bobby's Fluff" Published in Promotional Copy, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Zapp Magazine on Video -- Features Burkhart's Piece, "Bobby's Fluff", March 1994 (Box 46, Vhs 467.0018)
  - Short Stories and Other Writings, 1994-2013; cuid36228 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_50)
  - Poems, 1994-2014; cuid36229 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_49)
  - Poetry -- Typescripts, 1995; cuid36230 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Haikus, 1995-2012; cuid36231 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_47)
  - Ex Patriote: Some Journal Selections by Kathe Burkhart, 1996; cuid36232 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_45)
  - Short Story -- "Beffe van de Pijp", 1996, 2006, 2013; cuid36233 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_51)
  - Art Kitchen Magazine -- Writing and Art Contributions, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Literary Submissions -- Notes, Lists, 1999-2004, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Address and Mailing Lists, 1999-2007 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Short Story -- "Close Calls", 2000, 2003, 2013; cuid36234 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_52)
  - World Trade Center Haikus, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 2002-2011; cuid36235 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_39)
  - NYFA Funding -- Application Materials, circa 2002 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Book Printer Companies -- Notes, Invoices, Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - The Double Standard (2005) -- Excerpts, Edited Typescripts and Drafts, 1991-2005 (Box 20, Folder 12-13, Box 21, Folder 1-6)
  - The Double Standard (2005) -- Typescripts for Chapters, 1994-2008; cuid36236 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_53)
  - The Double Standard (2005) -- Translator Notes, Publishing Contracts, Page Layout Samples and Proofs, Book, Event Publicity, 1998-2007 (Box 21, Folder 7-12, Box 22, Folder 1-6)
  - Kathe Burkhart: Bad Girl: Works from 1983-2000 (2005) -- Cover Art, Description, and Book, 2005-2006; cuid36237 (Box 24, Folder 4, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_40)
  - Between the Lines (2006) -- Notes, Research, Copies of Photographs, Publishing Contracts, Correspondence, 2002-2004, undated (Box 22, Folder 7-13)
  - Between the Lines (2006) -- Early First Draft, Edited Typescripts, circa 2005 (Box 22, Folder 14, Box 23, Folder 1-9, Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Between the Lines (2006) -- Translations of French Reviews, Royalty Documentation, 2006-2008 (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
  - Between the Lines (2006) -- Book Proof Layout, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Between the Lines (2006) -- Research-Related, Grant Applications, and Correspondence, 2000-2013; cuid36238 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_41)
  - Short Story -- "Cells and the City" in Word For it: A Literary Review, circa 2005 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Kathe Burkhart. The Liz Taylor Series: The First 25 Years, 1982-2007 (2007) -- Press Release, Cover Design, cuid36239 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_48)
  - "Famous for 15 Seconds", 2007-2008 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - "Fair Ground" -- Edited Typescripts, circa 2008 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Reading at Crossing Border -- Image, 2009; cuid36240 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_42)
  - Emotional Weather -- Typescript, 2009, 2011; cuid36241 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_44)
  - Dudes (2014) -- Edited Typescripts, Drafts, Grant Applications, 1993-2014 (Box 24, Folder 8-13, Box 25, Folder 1-4, Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Dudes (2014) -- Typescripts of Chapters, 1994-2014; cuid36242 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_43)
  - Untitled Writing, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - "Excerpts from the Diary of a Teenage Girl in the Seventies" -- Drafts, Published version in Total Metal, undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - "Mandy and Me", undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Series IV. Graphic Design, 1981-2005; 6.84 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes, and 2 oversize flat boxes.
  Burkhart has worked as a graphic designer for clients including American Express, Coach, and Dutch East India Trading / Homestead Records. This series includes source image material, client work files, correspondence, and work samples. Work files can contain project sample boards, print layout sheets, and her design-related resume and business cards. Burkhart also designed cover art for some of her ex-husband Jozef van Wissem's music albums, of which there are proofs and CDs represented in this series. Her promotional fliers, advertisements, and album cover artwork for the Dutch East India Trading and Homestead Records during the 1980s are also in this series. Various other completed client samples in this series include advertisements, brochures, and magazine layout pages, which illustrate the breadth of her clientele, from jewelry companies to recording studios. She also worked on a number of book cover designs, including Country Herbs and American Country Living: The Ultimate Lifestyle Compendium. Copies of those books are in this series to fully represent her work, along with layout boards. There are also cover design work samples for Burkhart's own novel, From Under the 8-Ball, published in 1985.
  - Book Layout Boards -- Schism, American Country Living, and Other Clients, 1980s, 1991-1992, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Country Herbs and American Country Living: The Ultimate Lifestyle Compendium, 1991-1992 (Box 30)
  - Client Projects -- Homestead Records and Dutch East India Trading, 1986-1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 9, Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Design Work -- Related Resumes, circa 1986-1993 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Graphic Art Client Projects, 1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 11, Box 44, Folder 4-5)
  - Client Project -- Julia Morgan Book, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Client Project -- Lost and Found, circa 1991 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Blank Invoice Sheets, 1991, 1993, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Thread Waxing Space -- Poster With Artists and Writers Listed, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Client Project -- Jozef van Wissem CD Cover -- Layout, circa 2000 (Box 26, Folder 3, Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Burkhart Business Cards and Negative, Layout, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Layout for The Tekas Horn-O-Matic, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Junkie Layout, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Source Materials, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - "The Look of Los Angeles" Section, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Imagine a Future Peace? -- Poster, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Negatives of Posters, Stuff, and Items for Sale, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Living in the Police State" and "Miller: Merchandise Pricing and Strategy", undated (Box 27, Folder Unknown)
  - Layout Board -- "Nuclear Threats to Human Survival", undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
- Series V. Teaching, 1988-2018; 2.10 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes.; 487.4 Megabytes in 127 computer files.
  Burkhart has been a professor at New York University and similar arts-related institutions teaching courses often themed around issues of art, sex, activism, and feminism. This series contains support material for specific classes as well as files on the application and administration of her various appointments, dating from the late 1980s to the mid-2010s. Class titles including Drawing I and II; Sex and Contemporary Visual Art; Art and Activism; and Introduction to Critical Theory. Documentation related to these classes includes course descriptions, syllabi, reading lists, notes, student correspondence, and images and lists of artworks used as visual aids during lectures. A significant amount of paper and electronic files in this series relate to Burkhart's course Medusa's Laugh: Contemporary Feminist Concepts and Visual Culture dating from 2003 to 2010, and includes readings, syllabi, lecture notes, and reading questions.
  Files related to the administration of her teaching positions contain lists of courses taught in previous years, and correspondence referring to applications to various institutions including New York University, Columbia University, and School of Visual Arts. Application files include course descriptions, references, resumes, and images of her work. This series also includes a small collection of identification cards from various institutions where she taught, and teaching philosophy statements.
  - "The Discourse of Others: A Personal, Theoretical, and Historical Critique" -- Workshop Brochure, Fall 1988 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - "Approach to the Fragmentary: A Conceptual Approach to College" -- Brochure, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - "Discourse of Others" -- Workshop, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Reference Lists, and Teaching Philosophy Statements, 1990-1998, 2000-2017; cuid36243 (Box 26, Folder 9-10, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_57)
  - Class Readings, circa 1990, circa 1996, undated (Box 26, Folder 11-13, Box 31, Folder 1-2)
  - Drawing I and II, Spring 1992 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Teaching Notes, 1993-1994, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Letters for Visual Arts Presentations, 1993-1996 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Teaching Job References, 1994-1995 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence--from Students, 1994-1999 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Identification Cards, 1994-2015 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - School of Visual Arts -- Application Letter, Lecture Notes, Syllabus, 1996, 2012; cuid36244 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_66)
  - San Francisco Art Institute -- Notes and Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Drawing I and II -- Syllabi, 1998, undated; cuid36245 (Box 34, Folder 5, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_59)
  - Identity Politics and Aesthetic Expression -- Reading List, Course Proposal, and Notes, 1999-2000, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Sex and Contemporary Visual Art -- Syllabi, 2000-2011; cuid36246 (Box 31, Folder 13, Box 32, Folder 1-5, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_69)
  - Contemporary Art, 1976-2001 -- Syllabus and Reading Course Pack, Spring 2001 (Box 31, Folder 11-12)
  - Helene Cixous Lecture -- Notes and Related, 2001, 2006, 2010; cuid36247 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_61)
  - New York University -- List of Classes, Payroll Files, Correspondence, 2002, 2010-2014; cuid36248 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_65)
  - Medusa's Laugh: Contemporary Feminist Concepts and Visual Culture -- Readings, Syllabi, Lecture Notes, Reading Questions, 2003-2010, undated; cuid36249 (Box 32, Folder 6-8, Box 33, Folder 1-4, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_64)
  - Lecture Notes, circa 2003-2018 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Art and Activism -- Syllabus and Notes, Fall 2004 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Art and Activism -- Readings, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Art and Activism -- Course Description, 2006; cuid36250 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_54)
  - Images -- Class-related and Student Works, 2007-2013; cuid36251 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_62)
  - Sex and Contemporary Culture -- Syllabi and Exam Questions, 2010-2014; cuid36252 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_68)
  - Dream Courses Descriptions, 2011, 2014; cuid36253 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_60)
  - Columbia University -- Application Letter, Supporting Documents, 2011-2012; cuid36254 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_56)
  - Sex and Contemporary Art -- Syllabus, Description, and Readings, 2011-2013; cuid36255 (Box 33, Folder 8, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_67)
  - Sex and Contemporary Art -- Syllabi and Readings, 2012-2015 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Lecture -- "My Work", 2012; cuid36256 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_63)
  - CUNY Talk -- Notes, 2013; cuid36257 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_58)
  - List of New York University Classes Taught (2005-2012) and Related, 2013 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Bard College -- Application Letter, Dream Course Descriptions, 2014; cuid36258 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_55)
  - Introduction to Critical Theory -- Readings, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Painting III and IV -- Syllabus, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Teaching Philosophy Statement, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate Seminar -- Syllabus, undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Advanced Painting -- Syllabus and Reading List, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Notes, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Visual Culture -- List and Topics, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Sex Quiz, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Slides, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Interdisciplinary Art in Amsterdam -- Class Proposal, undated (Box 34, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Personal, 1969-2013; 7.75 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes, 1 record carton, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 1 flat-file folder.; 135.1 Megabytes in 185 computer files.; 5 audiocassettes; 1 videocassettes (vhs)
  This series contains personal material in paper and electronic form, containing correspondence, photographs, astrological readings, and school ephemera, as well as musical mix tapes and audio correspondence to a friend. Print and digital images include pets, travel, friends, ex-husband Jozef van Wissem, professional portraits of Burkhart, gallery and museum events, and interior images of her apartments/studios in both Amsterdam and New York. Her correspondence dates from the 1970s to the 2010s, with friends, romantic partners, and fellow artists. Martinsburg High School and Shepherd College ephemera includes a yearbook, graduation announcement, and class notes. Ephemera from CalArts, where she studied art in the 1980s, includes a graduation announcement and various student publications containing her artwork and writings. Other personal items in this series include address books, published interview profiles on Burkhart, pet passports and related, and astrological readings and recordings. Photographs and clippings from Burkhart's wedding ceremony/performance piece with Jozef van Wissem are in this series. Video recordings and further documentation of the performance piece can be found in Series I.
  - Childhood Poem, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Photograph Album, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Martinsburg High School -- Yearbook, Graduation Invite, and Diploma, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 16-17)
  - Correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 35, Folder 3-6, Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994-2011; cuid36259 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_467_ER_71)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 36, Folder 2-4)
  - Shepherd College -- Class and Personal Notes, 1976-1979 (Box 36, Folder 5-6, Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Dave (David) Cunningham -- Letters, Photographs, and Slides, 1980-1991 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Photographs -- Burkhart, Ex-Husband Jozef van Wissem, and Friends, 1980s-2000s (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
  - CalArts -- Student Publications and Graduation Announcement, 1981-1985, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 3-6)
  - "Hiroshima / Nagasaki. Whatever this Shit is. Bad. Awful", 1982-04-17 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0009)
  - Film by Paul Richmond, The Organization, 1984 (Box 46, Vhs 467.0016)
  - "60s to 80s Garage, Various, and Supremes. Totally Bitchen", 1986-09-28 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0014)
  - Pet Passports and Other Related Documentation, 1988-2013 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Autograph Book, 1989-1993 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Calendar and Planning Book, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Address Books and Contact Cards, 1990s, undated (Box 37, Folder 10-12)
  - Interviews and Quotes, 1990-2007 (Box 38, Folder 1, Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Wuthering Heights -- Gift, Book Inscribed by Burkhart's Mother, 1991 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - "Astrology Reading with Lexa", 1994-06-22 (Box 46, Audiocassette 467.0013)
  - Burkhart Business Cards, Identification, and Membership Cards, 1994, undated (Box 38, Folder 3)